Philip Scott

University of Waterloo, 2A Software Engineering

★ scottyfillups.io

scottyfillups

(705) 313-3189

pjscott@edu.uwaterloo.ca

Self-taught full-stack web developer, with numerous projects demonstrating expertise.

Passionate about learning; loves pushing the limits of new web technologies and exploring its applications.

Projects and people first; enjoys creating things people will enjoy and use. Technologies should be a means, not an end.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6), PHP, MySQL, C/C++, Scala, GLSL, HTML, CSS, XML, Markdown, Bash

Technologies: Node.js, Express, Handlebars, Redis, AngularJS, Heroku, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Mongoose, XPath, Apache

Tools: Git, NPM/Yarn, Webpack 3, Browserify, Babel, Bublé, Sass

Concepts: REST, OOP, AJAX, MVC, SQL injection, XSS, Salted Password Hashing, RegExps

Education

University of Waterloo

Candidate for Bachelor of Software Engineering

Class of 2021

Awards

Lieutenant Governor's Community Volunteer Awards for Students Government of Ontario 2016

President's Scholarship of Distinction

University of Waterloo 2016

Experience

AGF Investments Inc. Junior Web Developer

May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Successfully maintained public corporate website with over one thousand pages using the Cascade CMS
- Developed client-facing pages, built page templates using HTML/CSS and created an interface in Cascade for content management
- Interface stored data as XML; used the Velocity template engine and XPath to parse the data and insert into template
- Explored new technologies such as ChartJS, and provided stunning proof of concepts with objective insight as to whether it would be beneficial to use
- Spearheaded meetings with other departments discussing page specifications, such as studio and compliance

Windsor Manufacturing 3

Web Consultant

Jun 2016 - Jul 2016

- Managed hired Upwork developer tasked with developing corporate website
- Communicated specifications to developer with clarity and met deadlines

Projects

Strife 🔾

- Node.js chat application that generates room invitation URLs, similar to Discord
- Uses Socket.io for bi-directional communication and AngularJS for UI
- Chat history sanitized to prevent XSS attacks and stored using Redis
- Uses Mashape and Google RESTful APIs for reCAPTCHA and quote of the day

Vizplex 3

- Multivariable function visualization library that comes with Simplex3
- Allows developers to draw beautiful animated noise with WebGL
- Capable of animating noise, full screen, at 30FPS+ on an ordinary laptop
- Built with GLSL and JavaScript

Tumult 3

- Modular JavaScript noise library utilizing ES6 modules.
- Currently supports Perlin[1-4], Simplex[1-2] and Fractal noise
- Built with ES6 classes and transpiled using Bublé, a transpiler similar to Babel
- Generalized Perlin noise to the Nth dimension, see PerlinN

Volunteering

Peterborough Public Library

Computer Help Desk Volunteer

Nov 2012 - Apr 2016

- Helped library patrons with Userful Desktop, LibreOffice, email, Wi-Fi networks, printing documents, and questions
- Received a letter of recommendation for outstanding professionalism and technical prowess
- Received Lieutenant Governor's Community Volunteer Award for 300+ hours of volunteer work